Kind of a whole cat and mouse game of where they're going to show up next.
We'll be there in two minutes and see if we see anything.
I already told you, you need to stay on the sidewalk.
Then you can record, but stay on the sidewalk.
Everybody get in your car and follow. Follow them.
I woke up a Monday in September and my mom was saying,
hey, ICE is in West Chicago. We have to go.
We met up with some other patroller groups and leaders and got connected.
And then kind of since then, it's been no sleep, out all the time,
and just trying to find these guys.
For the last month, brothers Ben and Sam have spent their days
driving around the suburbs of West Chicago, tracking and documenting ICE arrests.
This is October the 16th and we have video confirmation
of ICE agents using the Illinois State Police headquarters parking lot.
The teenagers are both homeschooled and carve out five hours each day
to volunteer for a rapid response network that documents the arrests
and assists families of those detained.
What made you decide to do this?
My entire life, or at least my teenage years,
I've been very checked into the news and what's happening in the world.
But I've always felt kind of paralyzed in what I can actually do
because I'm just a high schooler in white suburbs of Illinois.
And then I woke up to ICE in my hometown.
In September, the Trump administration launched a major immigration crackdown in Illinois called Operation Midway Blitz.
More than 1,500 people have been swept up in the raids, according to the Department of Homeland Security.
The administration says they're targeting undocumented immigrants who are violent criminals.
But the reality is much different.
They say they're targeting, like, murderers and drug dealers.
It's like, no, you're targeting the wife who's working to support the family.
You're targeting the dad who is just trying to have his family be able to live.
If they're driving around, they're looking for somebody who's brown,
they jump out and they just, they grab them and then they disappear.
He's a citizen! He's a citizen!
We've gotten to places late where they've just taken somebody's husband with no criminal background.
Help!
Or we've gotten somewhere late where they've just taken somebody from a parking lot at a grocery store.
If we aren't there to film it, sometimes we don't get their names.
Sometimes they're just, they're just gone.
So we're usually looking for out-of-state plates and, like, bigger SUVs, usually pretty clean-looking and newer.
On the day we joined them, the brothers headed to a local courthouse.
Earlier today, there was an arrest made in this parking lot.
And there's another guy coming from the community for a hearing.
And we're just hoping that if ICE shows up, it can all be documented.